Guide to the Sir George Hubert Wilkins Papers
The Ohio State University. Byrd Polar and Climate Research Center Archival Program.
- Series III: Correspondence, 1908-1958; 1.5 cubic feet
  - Correspondence, 1949 (Box 12, Folder 41)
    Includes: Correspondence with: Bjarne Aagaard; A.D. Bajkov; Don Bate (Associated Clubs, Inc.); Brice?; Russell Bridges (Alkahest Celebrity Bureau); James P. Chapin (The Explorer's Club); Standish Chard (Radio Productions, Inc.); R.C. Cook (Mississippi Southern College); Russell Cower (The New York Times); Ethel Dodson (American Association of University Women); H.W. Eather (The Australian Society); Frank H. Ellis; Benjamin Franklin (Associated Clubs, Inc.); Andrew A. Freeman; Manson Glover (Glover Coating Company, Inc.); Welden F. Heald; Ralph M. Heintz; Charles Hendrix (U.S.S. Tiru); Howard Higgins (National Concert and Lecture Management); August Howard (American Polar Society); Grace M. Humphrey (Humphrey Lecture Management); Fenley Hunter; 'J.A.'; George H.T. Kimble (International Geographic Union); J.S. Kujawski (Dept. of The Army); J. Labarthe, Jr. (Mellon Institute of Industrial Research); J.W. Lawrence; Lemone?; Victor H. Lindlahr; C. Raymond Macaneu(?) (West High School); James F. Mathias (John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation); Franc Root McCreery; Eric Motzfeldt (The Canadian Club); John K. Northrop (Northrop Aircraft, Inc.); Culbert L. Olson (Olson, Olson & Olson); Russell Owen; Grace Sims Peat (Harold R. Peat, Inc.); C.T. Pedersen (Barnston Fur Farm); Finn Ronne; John W. Roular(?); Joseph Sadony (Education Research Laboratories); Ernest Sullivan; W. Stephen Thomas (Rochester Museum of Arts and Sciences); Thos J. Watson; H.W. Webb (Royal Societies Club); Suzanne Wilkins; Walter A. Wood (Arctic Institute of North America); Joseph L. Woodburn Jr. 2. Pamphlets, Newspaper clippings, invitations 3. Guest List, Third National Men of Science and Industry Dinner 4. "McGill University, Geography Summer School, 1949, Miscellaneous Information", + Address List 5. Personal notes, scribbles
  - Correspondence, 1950 (Box 12, Folder 42)
    Includes: Correspondence with: S.E. Alexander (Dept. of National Defence); Wes Baleria; C.E.W. Bean; Veldo H. Brewer (Tri-City Knife and Fork Club; Russell Bridges (Alkahest Celebrity Bureau); Oscar Brunler; H.A. Bruno; Chester Bryant; Canadian Army Staff College; Jack Cluett; Anne Coershell(?); L.H. Derrer (Canadian Army); W.Clement Dick (Canadian Army Staff College); Lavinia P. Dudley (The Encyclopedia Americana); Thomas Dunbabin (Australian High Commissioner's Office); Henry S. Evans (Radio and Television Committee); Benjamin Franklin (Associated Clubs, Inc.); Robert R. Hansen (Paraplegic Helpers Fund); F. Kenneth Hare (McGill University, Dept. of Geography); Ralph M. Heintz (The Ramohs); Ford Hicks (National Lecture Bureau, Inc.); Howard Higgins (National Concert and Lecture Management); Laurence Irving (Federal Security Agency, Arctic Health Research Center); E.A. Kendall; J. King (The Cunard Steam-Ship Company, Ltd.); Lauritz Liavaag; R.H. MacNeill (Hudson Bay Route Associates); T.H. McConica (American Ski Company); Walter J. McInnis (Eldredge-McInnis, Inc.); Eric W. Morse (The Association of Canadian Clubs); Guillermo Muller D.; Charles B. Newhall (Appalachian Mountain Club); Al Overton (The Ambassadors Club of Pittsburgh); Kenneth I. Ross (Explorers' Camp); William S. Sadler (Sadler and Associates); M.C. Shelesnyak; Harold M. Sherman; H.D. Shultz (Howard Nordlinger & Company); G.G. Simonds (National Defence College); J.E. Stephens (Republican Amphibian Seabee); H.E. Taber (Dept. of National Defence); M.C. Turner (The Dixie Bureau); Danton Walker; V.S. Watkins (Associated Clubs, Inc.); George F. Watson (the American Legion); Ethel Y. Wood (Associated Clubs, Inc.); A.E. Wrinch (Canadian Embassy) 2. Pamphlets, invitations 3. Adventurers' Club member list 4. Associated Clubs events calendar, travel schedule 5. "Special Bulletin on Lunchede Clubs"
  - Correspondence, 1951 (Box 12, Folder 43)
    Includes: 1. Correspondence with: 'J.A.'; Edward Arpee; William Bentley (McGill University, Board of Governors); Bill Bremmey(?); Russell Bridges (Alkahest Celebrity Bureau); Hawthorne Daniel; J.K. Davis; Wendell Phillips Dodge (The Explorers Club); Thomas Dunbabin (News and Information Bureau, Australia); Benjamin Franklin (Associated Clubs, Inc.); Donald S. Gates; Robert R. Hansen (The Desert Reporter); Eunice Hauskins (The Santa Fe Sinfonietta and Choral Society); Howard Higgins (National Concert and Lecture Management); Charles S. McVeigh, Jr. (Morris & McVeigh); McLachlen Banking Corp.; F. Frith Pickslay, Jr. (Gauranty Trust Company of New York); Joe Robinson; M.C. Shelesnyak; Helen Spindler (National Concert and Lecture Management); G.W.L. Townsend (The Australian Society of New York, Inc.); M.C. Turner (the Dixie Bureau); V.S. Watkins (Associated Clubs, Inc.); Clifford P. Wilson (Hudson's Bay Company); Ethel Y. Wood (Associated Clubs, Inc.) 2. Un-named letter, regarding meeting with Newspaper/Radio executive for sponsorship, Dunninger, Zenith Program, etc. 3. Un-named letter, Trip with Suzanne 4. Illegible name, mentions Chief Senior Scientist Dr. Skinner, Acting Executive Officer Captian E. Samnes 5. Farm Diary 6. "The Ohio Story" (No. 665 - "Antarctic Flight" 7. Statements of Account with Associated Clubs, Associated Executives Clubs 8. Associated Clubs Events Calendars, Speakers Date Confirmation slips 9. "Nominal Roll" - National Defence College 10. Guest List - Fifth National Men of Science and Industry Dinner 11. H.J.RES.291 - txt 12. Invitations, Pamphlets
  - Correspondence, 1952 (Box 12, Folder 44)
    Includes: 1. Correspondence with: Clara Adams; Helen Beckenlaugh(?); Leslie Gordon Bell; Russell Bridges (Alkahest Celebrity Bureau); Wayne G. Cook (Cook, Blair & Balluff); Cremmey(?); H.S. Currie (Truth and Sportsman, Ltd.); Richard M. Foose (American Association for the Advancement of Science); Ben Franklin (Associated Clubs, Inc.); Ralph M. Heintz; Howard Higgins (The School Assembly Service); Laurence Irving (American Association for the Advancement of Science); Preston E. James (Association of American Geographers, Annual Report); S.A. Kate (World biography); George H.T. Kimble (American Geographical Society); Dorothy E. Owles (Associated Clubs, Inc.); Grace Sims Peat. (Harold R. Peat Inc.); Val Rendle; Shelton E. Reynolds (Frederick Sasscer Parent-Teachers Association); M.C. Shelesnyak (The Weizmann Institute of Science); Donald R. Tarris(???); R.H. Vining (West Virginia Institute of Technology); Ewen Waterman (International Wool Secretariat); V.S. Watkins (Associated Clubs, Inc.); A.H. Wilkins; 'Winston'; Ethel Y. Wood (Associated Clubs, Inc.); Wm. W. Yardley (Alkahest Celebrity Bureau); David A. Young (American Psychiatric Association) 2. Farm Diary? 3. Speakers Date Confirmation Slips, "Information on Dates", "Travel Schedule", "Expenses", (Associated Clubs, Inc.) 4. Dates, Flight Schedule, Scraps
  - Correspondence, 1953 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    Includes: Correspondence with: J. Howard Beckenbaugh; Leslie Gordon Bell; Russell Bridges (Alkahest Celebrity Bureau); Bier Brown (Zenith Radio Corp.); Alan Campbell-Drury (Dept. of External Affairs); George Carroll (Journal American); Standish Chard; J.K. Davis; Benjamin Franklin (Associated Clubs, Inc.); Howard Higgins (The Redpath Bureau); Herman E. Klappert; Harry Byrd Kline (Washington Speakers Conference on Public Affairs); Mead Layne; Lowell; Edmund W. Nash (McGraw Hill Book Company, Inc.); Grace Sims Peat (Harold R. Peat, Inc.); H.W. Pier; H. Raaus(???); Russell Reid (Executives Club); Winston Ross; Robley D. Stevens; Charles Vanda (WCAU, Philadelphia); Harvey N. Volkmar (Geyer Advertizing, Inc.); Herbert J. Wilkins; Reginald Wood (Boy Scouts of America); Roderick M. Wright (Indiana House of Representatives) 2. "Statement by Mr. R.G. Casey, Minister for External Affairs, on the establishment of a scientific research station on the Antarctic mainland" 3. Information on Dates, Travel Schedules (Associated Clubs, Inc.)
  - Correspondence, 1954 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    Includes: Correspondence with: J.A. Allis (The Explorers Club); Brennan; Russell Bridges (Alkahest Celebrity Bureau); Alford Carleton (Aleppo College); Drouth(?); Harold M. Dudley (American Council of Commercial Laboratories, Inc.); Robert R. Hansen (TNT Productions); Meade Layne (Borderland Sciences Research Associates); Reynolds C. Mason; E.F. McDonald (Zenith Radio Corp.); Archibald McLachlen (McLachlen Banking Corp.); William J. Murphy (V.I.P. Service, Inc.); E.J. Purfield; Florence M. Read; Finn Ronne; W.A. Rundle; R.E. Shreck; Carl Werner Skogholm; Harold Smith; Chester Versteeg; Suzanne Wilkins 2. Invitation to Washington Speakers Conference; Restaurant Menu
  - Correspondence, 1955 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    Includes: Correspondence with: J.A. Allis; J. Brian Bird (McGill University); Russell Bridges (Alkahest Celebrity Bureau); S.S. Brown (Australian News and Information Bureau); L.O. Colbert (Arctic Institute of North America); J.K. Davis; H.M. Dudley (The Washington Pilgrimage); Earl; Harold H. Hart; Howard Higgins (Redpath Bureau); E.B. Hinckley (Babson Institute of Business Administration); Charles B. Hitchcock (American Geographical Society); Chas. H. Holmes (Walkabout Australian Geographical Magazine); A.R. Kapadia; Charles J. Keim; Lowell; Tom McConica (American Ski Company); Ernest N. Patty (University of Alaska); Biel Rundle (International Northwest Aviation Council); John Sampson (Kemsley Newspapers Ltd of London); Mark E. Smith Jr.; Anne Wilkins; Winston; Roderick M. Wright (Indiana House of Representatives); 2. Letter, illegible name 3. Herbert E. Budek Company, lest of "New Color Filmstrips of the American Geographical Society" 4. Pamphlets: McGill University, Washington Pilgrimage, 5. American Philosophical Society Calendar 6. Misc. Invitations, Notices of Appointments
  - Correspondence, 1956 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    Includes: 1. Correspondence with: Russell Bridges (Alkahest celebrity Bureau); Noel Ivan Burton; Cyril Clemens; Robert Cluett (US Coast Guard); J. Donovan (Dept. of External Affairs: Antarctic Division); Dorian & Company; Ruth & Harold Dudley (Washington Pilgrimage); Georgee Vilbart Douglas; Harold M. Dudley (Washington Liaison Service); Louis S. Edman (Optical Company); J. B. Foote; Goresline; Dan Hale; Harold H. Hart; Edward B. Hinckley; Charles B. Hitchcock (American Geographical Society); Roy Jansen; Charles J. Keim (University of Alaska); Serge A. Korff (Explorer's Club); P.G. Law; John P. Neal; E.E. Nishibori; Rodolfo N.M. Panzarini (Instituto Antarctico Argentino); George F. Pierrot (Fred Black Associates); Joseph Robinson; Finn Ronne; Rosie; Emory Ross (Albert Schweitzer Fellowship); R.B. Sawtell (Kimberly Clark Corp.); Robert C. Seyfried; George C. Starry; Paul-Emile Victor (Expeditions Polaires Francaises); Barrett Wilaughby; W.P. Williams (Burlington Hotel); 2. 'The Stature of a Man" by Addison A. Vestal (Albert Schweitzer Fellowship) 3. "Ronne Gets Antarctic Task To Head Weddell Sea Base", New York Times clipping
  - Correspondence, 1957 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    Includes: 1. Correspondence with: James A. Allis (to Mr. P.B. Law, Australian Dept. of External Affairs); Bruce Barton (Will Clayton, Hugh Moore); Darrel Brady; Gwendolyn Branch; Russell Bridges (Alkahest Celebrity Bureau); 'Darlyne'; Stephen L. Debalta; Harold M. Dudley (The Washington Pilgrimage); J. Glenn Dyer; Bob Engler; Arthur M. Fitts (Farmers and Mechanics Savings Bank); Robert P. Garnet; Roth Gene(?); John Hanessian; Austin Henschel; Howard Higgins (The Redpath Bureau); 'Jackie'; Jones; Warren H. Kulieke (The Urantia Brotherhood); J. Lauritzen; P.G. Law; J. De Lettera (Royal-Globe Insurance Group); 'The Littles'; Arthur Lush; MacFarland, Aveyard & Company; Douglas Mawson; Richard H. Miller; Grace Sims Peat; Percy; Dorothy G. Pope; Jack Rieger; Winthrop J. Robbins; Joseph Robinson; Emory Ross; R.A. Swan; Edward A. Rumely; Harold Sherman; Percy C. Spender; Evelyn Stefansson; John H. Tarris; Gordon Vaeth; Emile Walters; Ray J. Will; Hoke S. Wofford; James F. Griffin(?); 2. Polar Exploration Coers 3. Dept. of Public Printing and Stationary (Geographical Bulletin No. 8) 4. Anare Story 5. "Australian Explorer's Cairn Found in Antarctica"
  - Correspondence, 1958 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    Includes: 1. Correspondence with: John Bechervaise; James A. Bell; Brains & Brawn; Bill Breisky; Ralph P. Bridges; City Club of New York; Richard G. Coffin; Robert Cohen; Wilbur Cross; Raymond Daves; John S. Day; L.M. Dehl; Raymond M. Dinsmore; Preston A. Douglas; Harold M Dudley; C. Halliwell Duell; Robert H. Engler; Gil Fates; Wilson Follett; Boris Frank; Laurence M. Gould; Robert R. Hansen; Henderson; Howard Higgins (The Redpath Bureau); Edward B. Hinckley; Fenley Hunter; Arthur Joyce; F.K.; Ann Kaminsky (What's My Line?); Robert C. Keller; Serge A. Korff; H.J. Levensohn; Patricia T. Levine; John M. Lindsay; William R. Lowe; George H. Maines; Richard H. Miller; O'Connell; The Pelham Exchange; Henry Phillips; Terence M. Read; Philip L. Reed; E.A. Royce; USS Skate; H.R. Tarris; Paul H. Tobias; Russell A. Walkey; Stanley Wertheim; Herbert W. Williamson; Winston; Daniel H.H. Ingalls; Norman Gelison(?); H.M. Dudley (The Washington Pilgrimage); 2. Urantia Brotherhood (General Council, Member List), Statement of Receipts 3. Misc. Invitations, Pamphlets
  - Correspondence, undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
    Includes: 1. Correspondence with: J.A. Bath; Russell Bridges (Alkahest Celebrity Bureau); ALice McMurthe Biddle; Russell Clovece(?); Robert Couse; William Danice; J. Allan Dunn; Elliott; Frea; Greaves; Howard Higgins (The Redpath Bureau); Hildesheim; A.J. Kirshner; Sol Lesser; George Marstan; Ingrid Von Mater; Tom Mcarlic; R.J. Parsones; R.M. Pettit; Jean Philippe; Ward Randol; Ronald; Felice Swadof; Mr. Earl Thacker; Ed Uhl; Grace Underwood; Anne Wilkins; Winston; 2. Many, many illegible, handwritten notes
- Series IV: Expeditions/Trips, 1912-1940; 4 cubic feet
  The Expeditions/Trips Series includes the files of Wilkins' expeditions, and contains the following types of information: articles, correspondence, financial, legal, notes and reports. The following trips are documented: Balkan War 1912; Sandow Chocolate Company Photographic Project 1912; Trinidad/West Indies 1912-1913; Canadian Arctic Expedition with Stefansson 1913-1916; England to Australia Air Race 1919; British Imperial Antarctic Expedition 1919-1920; Shackleton Antarctic Expedition 1921-1922; Russia for the Quakers 1922-1923; Wilkins Australian and Island Expedition 1923-1925; Wilkins-Detroit Arctic Expeditions 1926-1928; Wilkins- Hearst Antarctic Expeditions 1928-1930; Graf Zeppelin Around the World Trip 1929; Wilkins-Ellsworth Trans-Arctic Submarine Expedition 1931; Ellsworth Antarctic Flight Expeditions 1930s; Hindenbrug Trip 1936;Soviet Search Expedition 1937;Second Submarine Expedition Plans 1937-1940.
  - Balkan War: Reports: Sir Hubert Wilkins - War Photographer for the Gaumont Company Cinematographers, London, 1912 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Sandow Chocolate Company Photographic Project: Christmas, 1912 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Trinidad and the West Indies, ca. 1912-1913 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Canadian Arctic Expedition with Vilhjalmur Stefansson (1913-1916), Correspondence and Legal Documents, 1913-1915 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Canadian Arctic Expedition with Vilhjalmur Stefansson (1913-1916), Notebook of George Hubert Wilkins, circa 1913-1914 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Canadian Arctic Expedition with Vilhjalmur Stefansson (1913-1916), Reports, circa 1913-1923 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - England to Australia Air Race, 1919-1920 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - England to Australia Air Race, Diary of George Hubert Wilkins, 1919 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - British Imperial Antarctic Expedition (1919-1920): Correspondence and Reports (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Shackleton Antarctic Expedition (1921-1922): Correspondence (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Shackleton Antarctic Expedition (1921-1922): Correspondence, letters to his mother by George Hubert Wilkins, September 1921- June 1922 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Shackleton Antarctic Expedition (1921-1922): Diary "Expedition Happenings", Januray-December 1921 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Shackleton Antarctic Expedition (1921-1922): Diary "Scientific", January-December 1921 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Shackleton Antarctic Expedition (1921-1922): Diaries, November-December 1921 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Shackleton Antarctic Expedition (1921-1922): Diary, January-March 1922 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Shackleton Antarctic Expedition (1921-1922): Diary, May-July 1922 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Shackleton Antarctic Expedition (1921-1922): Diary, July-September 1922 (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Shackleton Antarctic Expedition (1921-1922): Journal "Entomological/Geological" (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Shackleton Antarctic Expedition (1921-1922): Journal "Mammals" (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Shackleton Antarctic Expedition (1921-1922): Journals (two items) "Ornithological" (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Shackleton Antarctic Expedition (1921-1922): Report: Geological Observations by G. Vibert Douglas - Geologist to the Expedition, undated (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Shackleton Antarctic Expedition (1921-1922): Reports(Notes): of George H. Wilkins, Naturalist (Box 13.1, Folder 1)
  - Shackleton Antarctic Expedition (1921-1922): Reports, miscellaneous, 1921-1922 and 1943 (Box 13.1, Folder 2)
  - Shackleton Antarctic Expedition (1921-1922): Writings on by George H. Wilkins, undated (Box 13.1, Folder 3)
  - Russia for the Quakers, 1922-1923 (Box 13.1, Folder 4)
  - Wilkins Australian and Island Expedition: Correspondence, 1923-1925, ca. 1940s and undated (Box 13.1, Folder 5)
  - Wilkins Australian and Island Expedition: Field Notes, ca. 1923-1924 (Box 13.1, Folder 6)
  - Wilkins Australian and Island Expedition: Reports, 1923-1924 (Box 13.1, Folder 7)
  - Wilkins Australian and Island Expedition: Reports, 1923-1924 (Box 13.1, Folder 8)
  - Wilkins Australian and Island Expedition: Reports: Tribal Behavior/Traditions, 1924 (Box 13.1, Folder 9)
  - Wilkins-Detroit Arctic Expeditions: An Arctic Adventure by Howard H Mason, October, 1927 (Box 13.1, Folder 10)
  - Wilkins-Detroit Arctic Expeditions: Article: " Out of the North Came Two Dead Men " By Edward A Herron in Pageant, August, 1955 (Box 13.1, Folder 11)
  - Wilkins-Detroit Arctic Expeditions: Article: "Over the Top of the World" by Vilhjalmur Stefansson in The American Magazine, September, 1928 (Box 13.1, Folder 12)
  - Wilkins-Detroit Arctic Expeditions: Article: "Wilkins Goes Over the Top" by Burt McConnell in The Elks Magazine, June, 1928 (Box 13.1, Folder 13)
  - Wilkins-Detroit Arctic Expeditions: Books, 1930, 1932 (Box 13.1, Folder 14)
  - Wilkins-Detroit Arctic Expeditions: Correspondence, 1926-1927 (Box 13.1, Folder 15)
  - Wilkins-Detroit Arctic Expeditions: Correspondence, 1928-1929 (Box 13.1, Folder 16)
  - Wilkins-Detroit Arctic Expeditions: Description of Flights, undated (Box 13.1, Folder 17)
  - Wilkins-Detroit Arctic Expeditions: Report: Detroit Arctic Expedition, The: 1926 (The Detroit Arctic Expedition, 1926) (Box 13.1, Folder 18)
  - Wilkins-Detroit Arctic Expeditions: Detroit Aviation Society, 1926-1928 (Box 13.1, Folder 19)
  - Wilkins-Detroit Arctic Expeditions: Diaries, 1927 and 1928 (Box 13.1, Folder 20)
  - Wilkins-Detroit Arctic Expeditions: Financial and Plans of Operation, 1926 (Box 13.1, Folder 21)
  - Wilkins-Detroit Arctic Expeditions: Financial and Plans of Operation, 1927 (Box 13.1, Folder 22)
  - Wilkins-Detroit Arctic Expeditions: Flying the Arctic by Captain George Hubert Wilkins, 1928-1929 (Box 13.1, Folder 23)
  - Wilkins-Detroit Arctic Expeditions: Legal Records, 1927 and undated (Box 13.1, Folder 24)
    Lockheed Vega purchase agreement, 1927; Fokker purchase agreement, undated; Detroit News Agreement to sponsor expedition
  - Wilkins-Detroit Arctic Expeditions: Paper: "Arctic Flights" by Sir George Hubert Wilkins: Published by the Royal Aeronautical Society, 1928 (Box 13.1, Folder 25)
  - Wilkins-Detroit Arctic Expeditions: Plans of operation and flight chart, 1928 (Box 13.1, Folder 26)
  - Wilkins-Detroit Arctic Expeditions: Point Barrow to Spitzbergen Flight: Articles, 1928 (Box 13.1, Folder 27)
    See also news clippings for 1928
  - Wilkins-Detroit Arctic Expeditions: Point Barrow to Spitzbergen Flight: Log and Observation Charts, 1928 (Box 13.1, Folder 28)
  - Wilkins-Detroit Arctic Expeditions: Point Barrow to Spitzbergen Flight: Telegrams Conveying Congratulations, 1928 (Box 13.1, Folder 29)
  - Wilkins-Detroit Arctic Expeditions: Report: Flight over Arctic Ice from Point Barrow, Alaska - March 29 to April 22, 1927, May 2, 1927 (Box 13.1, Folder 30)
  - Wilkins-Detroit Arctic Expeditions: Report: Third year (1928) -Unedited copy (Box 13.1, Folder 31)
  - Wilkins-Detroit Arctic Expeditions: Report: "Draft of Report of the Detroit - Arctic Expedition" by Captain George Wilkins, 1928 (Box 13.1, Folder 32)
  - Wilkins-Detroit Arctic Expeditions: Report: "General Report: Detroit News - Wilkins Expedition, 1927" by George Hubert Wilkins (Box 13.1, Folder 33)
  - Wilkins-Hearst Antarctic Expedition: Article: "Wings Over the Wasteland" by Sir Hubert Wilkins: in The Sportsman Pilot, May, 1930 (Box 13.1, Folder 34)
  - Wilkins-Hearst Antarctic Expedition: Cable: T.V. Ranck to William Randolph Hearst, July 5, 1928 (Box 13.1, Folder 35)
    Wilkins' acceptance of Hearst's funds to sponsor Antarctic Expedition
  - Wilkins-Hearst Antarctic Expedition: Correspondence from British government officials concerning land acquisition, 1928-1929 (Box 13.1, Folder 36)
  - Wilkins-Hearst Antarctic Expedition: Correspondence, 1928-1930, 1949 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Wilkins-Hearst Antarctic Expedition: Diary, 1929 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Wilkins-Hearst Antarctic Expedition: Equipment and Supplies, 1928 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Wilkins-Hearst Antarctic Expedition: Financial, 1928-1930 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Wilkins-Hearst Antarctic Expedition: Notebook: Navigational Information and Notes, ca. 1929 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Wilkins-Hearst Antarctic Expedition: Photography, listing of negatives, undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Wilkins-Hearst Antarctic Expedition: Radiograms, 1928 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Wilkins-Hearst Antarctic Expedition: Report (Published):"Further Antarctic Explorations" :The Geographical Review, by Captain Sir Hubert Wilkins, 1930 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Wilkins-Hearst Antarctic Expedition: Report: "KOKA (Pittsburgh)to Broadcast Messages Weekly to Sir Hubert Wilkins in the Antarctic ", September 28, 1929 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Wilkins-Hearst Antarctic Expedition: Report (Published): "The Wilkins-Hearst Antarctic Expedition 1928-1929": The Geographical Review, by Captain Sir Hubert Wilkins, July, 1929 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Wilkins-Hearst Antarctic Expedition: Reports (manuscripts):Expeditions 1928-1929, and 1929-1930, 1928-1930 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Wilkins-Hearts Antarctic Expedition: Telegrams, ca. 1928-1930 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    Includes messages from Richard E Byrd and Byrd Station
  - Graf Zeppelin- Around the World Trip: "The Graf Zeppelin Around the World Flight," by Sir Hubert Wilkins, undated (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Graf Zeppelin - Around the World Trip: Correspondence and telegrams concerning, 1929-1984 (Box 14, Folder 14)
    Also includes 1935 Trans-Atlantic trip correspondence
  - Graf Zeppelin - Around the World Trip: Ephemera from, 1929 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Graf Zeppelin - Around the World Trip: In-flight news stories by Sir Hubert Wilkins, 1929 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Wilkins-Ellsworth Trans Arctic Submarine Expedition: American Geographical Society, 1930 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Wilkins-Ellsworth Trans Arctic Submarine Expedition: Announcement, 1931 (Box 14, Folder 18)